HI removed, cleaned
and corrected by Lunar Team
Self isn't something you find...
...it's something you create.
The more action you take...
...the more progress you make.
Self isn't something you find...
...it's something you create.
The more action you take,
the more progress you make.
Self isn't something you find...
...it's something you create.
The more action you take,
the more progress you make.
Self isn't something you find,
it's something you create.
- Arms, please.
- Mm-hm.
Okay. Lady in red. Guess.
She's, um, allergic to perfume.
- It's a good guess. She just sneezed.
- She's having an affair. Next?
Hold on. Having an affair?
You made that up.
Not at all. If you look closely,
she has a very peculiar...
My attitude towards life determines
life's attitude towards me.
You got a job to do, you do it right.
Stop.
Put your hands in the air now.
Make a federal case out of it.
Drop it. Drop the blanket.
Your hands, sir. Both hands.
- That's gratitude for you.
- Hey!
Put your hands above your head!
I bring you a gift and this is how
I'm treated?
- What gift?
- I dragged it three blocks.
Jane?
Pupils are dilated.
You on drugs, Mr., uh...?
Resnick. Carl Resnick.
I don't do drugs. Crack is wack.
Steady pulse.
Steady as a rock for someone...
- ...that dragged a body three blocks.
- Let me handle this, Jane. I'll do it.
So this is a gift?
Is that why you brought her here to us?
Her? Them.
There's more than one?
It's a whole bagful, fella.
What do you need, glasses?
- A bagful of what?
- Potatoes.
Potatoes.
I'm supposed to deliver them
to the police.
Near enough.
- He's a perfect subject.
- Subject?
To plant a suggestion.
He's hypnotized.
- He's lying.
- Is he?
Given that the girl he dragged in is not
actually a bag of spuds, then yeah.
It's not lying if he believes it.
True. Thank you.
So, Carl. Why would you bring
a bag of potatoes to the police?
- I don't... I... I can't...
- Potatoes to cops.
Potatoes.
Not doughnuts, but potatoes.
Someone tell you to do it?
- Yes. Yes.
- Who?
Uh...
- I can't remember.
- Try.
I'm trying.
What if I told you it wasn't potatoes?
That in fact it was a dead girl
you were dragging around.
You have a twisted sense of humor.
Here's proof, Carl.
What do you see there?
Potatoes.
He is crazy.
- Nope. Just hypnotized.
- Oh, come on.
Hypnosis is just a way to connect
to the imagination...
...rather than the conscious mind.
The mind will accept whatever
the imagination creates, however bizarre.
Hypnotism is what you use
against my explicit orders...
...to get witnesses to tell the truth.
That's different than convincing someone
a dead girl is a sack of vegetables.
Different in scale.
He doesn't look like he's in a trance.
Neither did Minelli when I
hypnotized him to stop smoking.
The subject acts normally,
except inside the suggestion.
Carl's suggestion had this very
powerful hallucination.
And to forget who did this...
Whoever hypnotized him,
I gotta say, good.
Good enough to hypnotize
Carl into killing a girl?
Depends on whether deep down,
Carl really wanted to kill the girl.
But he's hypnotized.
Uh-uh.
No suggestion makes you do
something against your moral character.
Against your true will.
A hypnotized saint is still a saint.
Not that he's a saint.
So if Carl's a killer, he can be
hypnotized to kill. Otherwise...
Otherwise the hypnotist killed the girl
and framed Carl.
Rigsby.
So, is Carl a killer?
What did we find out?
Sells cars, boats, stuff like that.
And you know this how?
Well, he's very well-mannered.
A little over-groomed...
...too badly dressed to be gay.
So salesman.
He works at a dealership
over on Fulton.
- Does he have a record?
- Not even a parking ticket.
He's a good boy. Obeys authority.
A perfect subject for a trance.
He's all soft and squishy
and malleable.
Can you fix him?
Lift the trance,
make him remember what happened?
I could try, but without knowing
the trigger it would be like you and I...
...playing Marco Polo in the Atlantic.
Take forever and you get all pruny.
Easier just to find the hypnotist
and ask him.
Got an ID on the victim. Her fingerprints
were on file with the school board.
She's Mary Beth Hendrix, 27. Her
sister's on the way from the airport now.
Mm. That's Mary Beth.
She, uh...?
Someone shot her?
A gunshot wound to the head,
I'm sorry.
The coroner says she died instantly.
I can't believe it.
She was fine when I left.
You lived together?
Um, yeah.
Two country girls in the big city.
I didn't want to come here, but...
...Mary Beth said she'd take care of me.
That's funny, huh?
Lindsay? Your trip. To San Francisco?
Um, just overnight. For work.
I had just landed when you called.
Mary Beth's an elementary
school teacher, right?
She was. Yeah. But last year
I got her a job where I work.
At the Model Life Center, downtown.
Mary Beth was the boss' assistant.
And I'm an event planner.
I help the doctor plan NLP seminars
around the country.
- What's NLP?
- Neurolinguistic programming.
Sneaky ways to influence people
doesn't sound quite as catchy.
- Dr. Daniel changes lives.
- Royston Daniel?
Yes. He's the best.
Uh-huh.
Who's Royston Daniel?
Dr. Royston Daniel is one of the
country's pre-eminent hypnotherapists.
Mary Beth is dead? Oh, my God.
You knew Mary Beth, then?
Sure. I met her
at the Model Life Center.
I'm taking Dr. Daniel's NLP course.
Help me be a better salesman.
Did you spend a lot of time
with Mary Beth?
At the Monday class.
I didn't understand the exercise.
Mary Beth spent her whole lunch
explaining it to me.
She was a great teacher.
Patient, you know?
Even with a dope like me.
So now do you remember
who hypnotized you?
I got nothing. I'm sorry.
But Mary Beth, what happened to her?
We should go take a look at Daniel
and this Model Life Center.
- Let's bring Carl.
- What for?
It's where the hypnotists are.
Carl is still our prime suspect in this.
We can't use him as bait.
As long as we don't lose him or
break him, what's the problem?
"Get What You Want
From Whoever You Want." Scam.
Not to mention bad grammar.
Neurolinguistic programming
is not a scam.
It's the science of
willpower and persuasion.
Communicating more deeply.
A way to better your life.
- Scam.
- Scam that can better your life.
Deep. You two stay here.
Good afternoon.
My name is Dr. Royston Daniel.
And I'm going to teach you the secrets
of neurolinguistic programming.
Many of you may not believe
in the power of trance...
...but I promise, you will.
Excuse me, young man.
This is not the moment.
Wake.
What's going on?
Dr. Daniel, what happened?
A round of applause for Mike here
for being such a good sport.
As you may know,
I am Dr. Royston Daniel.
You're all here because
you want something.
You want power.
You want money.
You want love. You want...
- I want a quick word with you privately.
- I'm in the middle of something.
- It's very important. It's about your boat.
- My boat? I don't have a boat.
No, it's on fire.
- Rick, get security. Look, I don't know...
- Sir.
Your assistant Mary Beth
has been murdered.
California Bureau of Investigation.
Like to speak with you.
You're gonna have to excuse me, folks.
My associate, Mr. Rick Tiegler,
will conduct the seminar from here on in.
I hope to see you again soon.
Okay.
Okay, good. As Dr. Daniel has shown,
trance is incredibly powerful.
We're going to teach you how to
unleash that power for yourselves.
Let's start by relaxing with a few
simple breathing exercises.
Then we'll show you how to
supercharge your life.
How does that sound?
Hi, Dr. Daniel.
Carl? Is this who hypnotized you?
Let's have a look at those eyes.
- Hey.
- Jane.
Do you know this man?
His face is familiar.
Is he one of my students?
Hmm.
- No.
- Rigsby, speak to Dr. Daniel.
Take Jane with you.
Carl and I are going back to the seminar.
That way I know
he won't get lost or broken.
- Could we use your office?
- Yes, it's this way.
I'll catch up.
This is terrible. Poor girl.
I had a bad feeling when she didn't come
in this morning. Not like her to disappear.
She have any problems lately?
Bad breakup?
Anybody who might want to hurt her?
I wouldn't know. Mary Beth's
personal life was her own.
She was brought in to us
by Carl Resnick.
He was hypnotized to think
she was a big bag of potatoes.
- Hmm. Strong stuff.
- That's an old shot. Heh.
Who could have done that?
Oh, very few people have the talent to
create a trance that powerful. Very few.
Other than you, of course.
Mm.
Where were you last night
between midnight and 6?
Oh, wait now.
You think I killed Mary Beth?
Did you?
- Well, maybe I need a lawyer here.
- Maybe. I wouldn't have a clue.
Rigsby? He gonna need a lawyer?
Tell us about your students.
Who wants to get "whatever they want
from whoever they want"?
Who wouldn't want to make
their life better?
Using trance as a tool, NLP can help
everyone from insomniac soccer moms...
...to high-powered executives.
Smokers, weight challenged,
anyone who wants to improve his life.
And control the lives of others?
Some of my students want to sell
to their customers better.
Or make people like and respect them.
There's nothing wrong with that, right?
Oh, excuse me.
Royston, I just have the files...
...for the advance work for the
seminar in San Francisco.
- Lindsay, you came in.
- Yeah.
I had to keep busy, you know.
Thanks. But you don't
belong here, not today.
Whatever this is can wait.
It's not important.
Well...
I'm otherwise occupied,
as you can see. Go home.
Grieve. Don't worry about us,
we'll survive. Take care of you.
Right. I'm sorry, this was a...
Was a bad idea. Sorry.
I'm sorry.
"Take care of you."
That's the smoothest blow-off
I've heard all day.
I have a question for you guys.
- Are you feeling it?
- Yes!
- Are you guys feeling it?
- Yes.
All right. Now I'm gonna
talk to you individually...
...and I may ask
one or two of you onstage.
Would you do that? Would you
come up on stage and help me?
- What are you doing here?
- What do you want me to do here?
I'm sorry, I thought you were
someone else.
- Sir.
- I'll be right back.
Mr. Tiegler. Stop!
Mr. Tiegler.
- Didn't like the class?
- Cuffs.
Looks like I caught the
mystery hypnotist.
Got what you want
from who you want.
NLP stuff seems to work.
I'm not talking about Carl.
I don't know anything about him.
Let's talk about your job.
Agent Rigsby asked around at the Center.
Everyone says you're Dr. Daniel's
number one guy.
I'm proud to assist Dr. Daniel.
And I'm good at what I do.
That's what the model life
is all about.
If anyone could put the hex
on Carl Resnick, it's you.
I wouldn't say that. No.
You ever try your stuff
on Mary Beth Hendrix?
- I'm not talking about her.
- Are you a drinker?
Would you like one now?
- You offering?
- No.
I'm not a drunk.
I'm under a lot of stress.
I understand. Were you drunk when
you killed Mary Beth?
- I didn't.
- That's right, you didn't.
If you were drunk,
you had diminished capacity.
You're not responsible
like you normally would be.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
Yeah, I know that.
Well? Is that how it was?
Maybe. I... I don't really know.
- Tell me what happened.
- Yesterday, I...
I kind of asked Mary Beth out...
...and she said no.
Actually, she said "no way in hell."
So last night you were mad.
Maybe went to a bar to forget.
Yeah, I kind of hoisted a few. Dozen.
But I mean, come on, everybody needs
to let off a little steam, right?
I lasted till about 1
and then I kind of blacked out.
And then, when I woke up...
...it was 5 a.m. and I was in
Mary Beth's living room.
I was standing over her body.
I was holding a gun.
I could smell the powder, but...
...I was just standing there...
...as calm as could be.
So you killed her.
Yeah, I guess I did.
But like you said, I'm not responsible.
And after you killed her...
...that's when you used
your skills to frame Carl Resnick?
We'd been partners
in a trance exercise.
I had put him under a couple of times.
After that it just gets easier.
Especially with someone like Carl.
He's such a cream puff.
And when Carl dragged
a murdered girl's body to the cops?
Did you think Carl was
getting out of there alive?
- Well, I...
- Rick.
We're charging you with the murder
of Mary Beth. Stay put.
- Really?
- Really.
Be with you in just a sec.
Oh, hey, boss.
Has Cho searched Tiegler's place yet?
He's getting the warrant.
I finished the student interviews.
- How's it going here?
- A couple more teachers to go.
Nobody knows
anything about Mary Beth or Tiegler.
I can't believe Rick killed Mary Beth.
Think Dr. Daniel will set up a place
to make donations in her name?
A charity for a school would be good.
- He's still here?
- Yeah.
I've been helping Rigsby
parse the submodalities...
...of the teachers' language patterns.
Translating the doubletalk.
Reframing...
...pacing, representational systems.
I don't get half of
what these guys say.
- What are you doing?
- What? Nothing.
Are you mimicking me?
It's called modeling.
You model yourself on your subject.
Subject?
You're not trying this NLP crap on me?
No. Sort of.
You said this would establish a rapport.
Heh. Well, it needs work. I'm going back
to the office. See me when you're done.
I don't believe this NLP stuff
works at all.
You will.
- No pineapple on this one.
- Mm.
- Oh, no, thanks.
- You have to.
- It's tradition. The case is closed.
- Hm.
"Hm"? There's no "hm" on this one.
We found the gun that
killed Mary Beth...
...in Tiegler's apartment,
with his prints.
Plus, you know, the confession.
Rick Tiegler's black out
strike you odd?
He got drunk, he blacked out, killed
someone. Who hasn't been there?
Kidding.
Tiegler came out of a drunken
stupor standing upright over a body...
...instead of facedown
in a pool of vomit.
Sounds more like
a trance than a black out.
Somebody hypnotized Tiegler into
killing Mary Beth and hypnotizing Carl.
It's possible.
I didn't eat all this grease for nothing.
This case is closed. You're just seeing
suggestion everywhere, Jane.
- You're too suggestible.
- Hm.
Oh, right, too much
of a control freak for that?
Pot, meet kettle. Kettle, pot.
Hi, Agent Lisbon. I'm here for my
sister's effects, from our apartment.
- Agent Rigsby will help you.
- Thank you.
Ms. Hendrix, do you believe
Rick Tiegler killed your sister?
Jane.
Actually, I kind of don't.
- How did you know?
- Why don't you come to my office?
I'm so sorry to be such a bother.
Control freak.
I'm so sorry to be bothering you guys.
What exactly is your concern,
Lindsay?
It's just been nagging at me.
Did, um...
Did Rick say how he got
into our apartment?
No, he said he was blacked out. Why?
Mary Beth, she really disliked him.
I mean, really, really disliked him.
I can't imagine she would
open the door, let him into our place.
He couldn't have broken in.
The BFS report says the
front door wasn't damaged.
I don't get it. I mean,
we had a deadbolt and a peephole.
She was security conscious since
she and Royston got mugged.
She and Dr. Daniel?
When he took her to Maui
for the weekend.
Some kids, they mugged them.
It was awful.
- She and Dr. Daniel were dating?
- For six months now.
I thought he told you.
And, voila.
- Would you excuse us for a minute?
- Yeah.
Daniel told us Mary Beth
was just his assistant.
Didn't know about her private life.
So Daniel lied to us. Why?
- Well, embarrassment, fear, privacy.
- Guilt, maybe?
Probably nothing, but it's a loose end.
That Tiegler's attorney
could hang us with.
We better go pick up Daniel.
If we walk, you can burn
some case-closed pizza calories.
Cute.
Go inside and find out everything about
her sister's relationship with Daniel.
Okay.
Hey, Lindsay, I want you to tell me
when...
...Mary Beth started dating Dr. Daniel.
Royston would never hurt Mary Beth.
Not in a million years,
if that's what you're thinking.
- I really am quite busy, you know.
- We'll have you back here very soon.
Tell me what this is about.
- Just a few questions, that's all.
- Yes, a few questions about what?
I'm not sure,
I won't be the one asking.
Oh, come on, agent. Just a hint.
You know, you're far too pretty
to be so solemn.
Ah, the curse of the pretty girl.
You've been told you're gorgeous
since you were 12.
Now you can't bear to hear
what most women long for.
I have a job to do, that's all.
Are you really that tough?
I didn't think so.
- You don't know anything about me.
- No?
No.
You're ambitious.
More than you'll let anyone see.
A girl from Nowheresville
desperate to make it big.
You worry you'll always
be small-town, small-time...
...that you haven't got what it takes.
And that's why you're so shut down
to everything but this job.
Dr. Daniel?
No offense...
...but I've been working
with Patrick Jane for nine months now.
You wanna get under my skin,
you're gonna have to up your game.
Shall we?
I'll tell you again, Agent Cho.
I wasn't sleeping with my assistant.
Assistant's sister says different, doctor.
Then she's lying or misled somehow.
In November, the two of you
didn't go to Paris?
On business, yes.
I travel extensively, teaching.
Same story for 23 minutes now.
Maybe he's telling the truth.
Maybe it's Lindsay Hendrix who's lying.
No. This one's lying.
Notice how he can't break
eye contact?
I'll get the truth out of him.
Look, agent,
I came here out of courtesy.
Now, if there's nothing new,
I'd like to go.
- Hey, Cho, may I?
- Sure.
Dr. Daniel, tell the truth.
You'll feel better. Trust me.
I'd like to go now.
- Hey, hey, hey!
- When you tell the truth.
- Whoa.
- All right. We were together.
We've been dating
since September, okay?
- Feels better, doesn't it?
- Rigsby, outside.
You broke my nose,
you crazy bastard.
- I'm fine, it's just...
- Gun and badge.
- Boss, come on.
- Now.
Damn it, Wayne.
Do you understand what you just did?
- Oh, dear.
- I know.
- No. No, this.
- No. No way.
Yeah, afraid so, he's been hypnotized.
Oh, dear.
- Oh, I've been hypnotized, have I?
- Mm-hm.
You gonna make me
do embarrassing things?
Pretend I'm Tina Turner or something?
- You wanna be like Tina Turner?
- Ha, ha.
Jane, trust me. I'm not hypnotized.
I feel fine. Totally normal.
Normally you don't break the noses
of suspects.
What are you talking about?
I just questioned the guy.
Do you think
this could be psychological?
Like some sort of psychotic break?
No. Hypnosis, that's all.
I thought you couldn't hypnotize
somebody against his moral character.
Rigsby has a brutal streak.
If you didn't know, now you know.
It's not an uncommon trait in those
that choose to go into police work.
- I'm calling a shrink anyway.
- No, wait.
Deeply hypnotized subjects
are suggestible, have little inhibition.
Rigsby, do me a favor. Close your eyes.
Please.
Now, relax.
Don't tell me, but think about it.
Think about what you most
wanna be doing right now.
You can do anything you like
in the whole world.
What are you gonna do?
I want you to open your eyes
and do it.
Do whatever you like.
Oh, yeah.
That's what I'm talking about.
- Hm.
- Okay, he's hypnotized.
- Well, unhypnotize him.
- You sure?
- Do it.
- I can't.
The hypnotist uses a specific trigger
to induce a trance.
Unless I know that trigger,
I can't get him out.
- I have to go.
- Where do you have to go to?
- I can't tell you. I'll see you later.
- Rigsby, no.
No, no, this is good.
This is very good.
He's not a guinea pig.
- Rigsby, stay here. That's an order.
- I'm sorry, boss. I have to go.
You can't leave. You're not well.
- Stop messing around, I'm fine.
- Hey.
Talk to him, Grace. He'll listen to you.
Rigsby.
Please stay. Please.
Okay. But not for long.
- Come on, come sit with me.
- Okay.
- Rigsby didn't talk to Tiegler, did he?
- Nope.
So Tiegler didn't do this.
Maybe he didn't kill Mary Beth either.
Looks like you're right.
Tiegler was put in a trance by the
real killer and thought he blacked out.
- Same person put Rigsby under.
- We'll question everybody...
...Rigsby interviewed at the NLP center
and anyone he talked to.
Has to be Daniel.
He's the only one with the chops.
He lied about sleeping with the victim.
Whoa. Why would he want Rigsby
to smack his own face into the table?
Why would anyone want Rigsby
to smack Daniel's face?
My guess,
the smacking of the face into the table...
...unintended side effect
of a deeper hypnotic command.
- Command to do what?
- There's the rub. Let's find out.
- I do not need this right now.
- Jane's off doing his thing?
Yes, and I should be with him.
What the hell happened?
- Tiegler got bail just like that?
- No record and he's not a flight risk.
Plus Judge Milton set the bail
at 50,000.
Fifty thousand dollars
for an accessory to murder charge?
Well, that's the thing.
ADA dropped it to obstruction.
A deal? I was not consulted.
Tiegler found some juice somewhere.
Got a defense attorney
from Horton & Fleer, whole nine.
- Find out about Tiegler's bail.
- Right.
Hello, agents. Nice day, huh,
to be walking free in the world?
You need supervision.
We think you might have been
hypnotized by Mary Beth's killer.
Really? That's your play?
- You could be in danger, sir.
- You're the danger, lady.
You threw me down a marble staircase.
- Look at this bruise.
- No, thanks.
What if I'm right? What if you were
hypnotized to take the blame...
...for her murder and the killer's still
out there. That makes you a loose end.
You cops will try anything
to make me doubt myself.
You and my mother. It's not
gonna work. I'm living the model life.
You have a very good day, Agent Lisbon.
Try not to bruise anyone.
- Tiegler's bond? Tiegler didn't post it.
- Who did?
The Model Life Center, Incorporated.
- Really?
- Yeah.
- Look into it.
- Okay.
I gotta get back.
Why are we here?
I wanted to bring him somewhere
where he felt safe, relaxed.
Something that brought him back to his
childhood. Before he started getting hurt.
- Hurt by who?
- Yeah, hurt by who?
Well, whoever. None of my business.
Here we are. Please, have a seat.
- Nobody hurt me, okay?
- Jane, don't upset him.
- I know what I'm doing.
- You still on this hypnosis kick?
I'm telling you, you're wrong.
Rigsby, I'm gonna have to ask you
to trust me, okay?
Try and trust me.
Gonna help you break this trance.
No one's gonna hurt you, okay?
I'll bring you back to your normal self.
You'd like that, wouldn't you?
- You've got it wrong.
- Maybe so.
Everybody makes mistakes,
don't they?
That's life, huh? Ups and downs.
Look at those swings. Up and down.
Up and down.
That's life.
Relax into it.
Nothing to worry about.
Up and down.
How are you feeling, good?
Tingling in your hands? Buzzing?
- Tingling, I guess, a little.
- That's good.
Now, you're watching those swings.
Up and down.
Let yourself drift away.
Feel the tension release.
Watching the swings.
You're doing it all on your own.
That's very good.
All on your own.
Now I have to find the hypnotic trigger.
Could be visual, auditory, or physical.
Watching the swings.
- Dude, don't feel me up, man.
- Deep breathing.
Breathe in, feel the breath.
Feel the breath out.
In and out.
- That's good.
- Jane, stop.
- What?
- Just... Okay.
I have a splitting headache, just...
- Just breathing.
- Step off.
Just breathing.
Nobody's hurting you.
No, you are. You're hurting me.
Stop it.
Stop doing your stuff on me.
Your reaction is part of the suggestion.
A built-in defense mechanism to stop me.
- Rigsby, let Jane help.
- Stop. I've gotta get to...
- I've gotta go. I've gotta get out of here.
- Wayne, stop.
He's in too deep. You try to stop him,
he'll probably hurt you.
- Hello, Dr. Daniel.
- Agent Rigsby.
Thank God you're here. Help me.
Shut up, Royston.
Wayne, thank you for coming.
Thank you for helping me.
- I had to come.
- I know.
Hey, Lindsay, I want you to tell me
when...
...Mary Beth started dating Dr. Daniel.
Royston would never hurt Mary Beth.
Not in a million years.
This is just routine.
Relax, we'll be done in no time.
I will, I'll relax.
I feel very relaxed with you, Wayne.
Very safe.
Very safe and relaxed
sitting next to you.
I feel like I could tell you anything.
Anything at all.
Let me tell you about Dr. Daniel.
I know.
Don't worry.
Everything's gonna be fine now.
Agent Rigsby.
Agent, I want you to relax and listen
very carefully to the sound of my voice.
You've got to listen to me,
for God's sake. You've...
I was so in love with you,
you arrogant bastard.
And all you wanted was Mary Beth.
That stupid cow.
I thought that if I could get rid of her,
that you would see me.
And love me for who I am.
But you were in San Francisco
when Mary Beth was murdered.
Yeah. But they have these things
called rental cars.
And I drove up there,
and I did the deed.
I hypnotized that skeezebag,
Rick, to take the blame for it.
Got back just in time
to catch my flight.
When I got off the plane I thought
Royston and I would be together.
That he would see me
for the gifts that I have.
- But he didn't see you.
- No, he didn't.
- It's hard when they don't see you.
- What a moron I was.
What a moron.
I came to you and you said to me:
"Oh, it's not important.
We'll do fine without you. Go home."
Do you remember that?
Look at me.
And I knew in that moment
that you would never love me.
Never.
So now you're gonna die.
Rigsby, he hurt me.
He hurt me, Rigsby.
You love to protect women,
don't you?
I saw how you looked
at that red-haired agent.
Grace. Her name's Grace.
Wayne, I need your protection
right now.
I need your help with a special job.
- You'll help me, won't you?
- Sure, what do you need me to do?
- I need you to...
- Hello, Rigsby.
Hey, is that Venus or Mercury?
Hansel and Gretel had bread crumbs,
I had Rigsby.
I knew he'd lead me to the guilty one.
I put a tracking device in his pocket.
- Bingo.
- Smart.
Except for the part
where I have the gun.
Oh, I have a gun, too. Lisbon?
Drop the weapon.
So predictable. Rick.
You should put the gun down now.
Oh, for heaven's sake.
Drop the weapon, Agent Lisbon.
Tiegler, this is your first day
out on bail, don't...
Shut up! I said drop it.
Best do as she says.
Well, I'm impressed, Lindsay.
There's not three people in the world
could have done an induction on a cop.
But Rigsby's guard was up
when he was with Dr. Daniel and Carl.
And you? You just crept through
the cracks, you sneaky little mouse.
I was never the sparkling,
vivacious one.
That was Mary Beth,
and all the boys loved her.
Never me.
Until I went to work for Dr. Daniel.
Then I realized I have a talent
for reaching peoples' unconscious.
People let their defenses down
with me.
They trust me.
Finally I was worth something.
Finally I'm in control.
Look around yourself.
Are you in control now?
All these people here have to die.
That's not control. That's madness.
You're having a nervous breakdown,
Lindsay.
You need help.
We can help you.
It's a beautiful night for a swim,
don't you think?
Yeah.
The ocean is so nice tonight.
Hear the crash of the waves, Rigsby?
- It's peaceful.
- Yeah. It's nice.
It's not nice, Rigsby,
it's not the ocean.
Take Royston for a little swim.
- Show him that dark, beautiful ocean.
- No.
That's right. Take him for a swim.
I love night swims. Don't you?
Stop.
Rigsby, don't.
Rigsby, listen to me,
listen to my voice.
Why don't you take Jane for a swim?
I think he wants to go.
- I don't want to.
- Rigsby!
Come on, let's go swimming, Jane.
No, it's not water down there,
it's concrete.
The water's gorgeous. Mr. Jane
loves to swim just like you do.
Stop, Rigsby.
Take him for a swim.
Take him over. He wants to go.
- Push him over, Rigsby.
- No. Shark.
Shark. There. See it?
It's a great white.
- Sharks?
- There's no sharks. The water's fine.
- She's lying. She wants you eaten.
- Throw him in!
- Throw him over. Throw him over.
- Who is this woman?
- Don't...
- Shoulder?
- Throw him in, Rigsby.
- Shoulder. Wait.
- Wait.
- Throw him in.
Yes. Gun. Thanks, Rigsby.
You, my friend,
have been in a trance state.
- Get out of here. Come on.
- Oh, I'd love to.
Let's go.
Jane, would you untie him?
Come on.
I don't know,
I just suddenly came out of it.
- Then, boom. I just had to take her down.
- You took down a 100-pound woman.
- In that context, you did good.
- What do you mean, "in that context?"
In the context of someone
letting himself get hypnotized...
...nearly throwing his colleague
off a building and then...
...finally being able to overpower a small,
crazy woman to retrieve the situation...
...you did okay.
Be fair, a small crazy woman with a gun.
A gun is a gun.
And anyone can be hypnotized.
She was very good.
Very good. Not as good as me,
but close. Close-ish.
Which is why
the Professional Standards Unit...
...has cleared you for assaulting
Dr. Daniel.
You weren't yourself.
But he is now, right? Himself?
- Completely unprogrammed?
- Yes, he is.
Last two days are gone,
but other than that I'm good to go.
Oh. So you don't remember anything
from when you were hypnotized?
Fragments, but no, not really.
- Thank goodness, right? Heh-heh-heh.
- Yeah.
Oh, Lord, did I make a fool of myself?
Cluck like a chicken?
- I didn't do Tina Turner, did I?
- No.
You were perfectly normal.
Well, good. That's a relief, eh?
- Coward.
- What?
You honestly don't remember it?
- Don't remember what?
- He remembers.
He so remembers.
What?
It'll come to you.